<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bastian Gruber</title>
    <link>http://gruberbastian.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bastian Gruber</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 08:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gruberbastian.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: One month of focus</title>
      <link>http://gruberbastian.com/post/project-one-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gruberbastian.com/post/project-one-month/</guid>
      <description>The dilemma of our privilidged and comfortable lifes as software engineers is:
 There are always so many new things to get into and play around with After playing around with them enough, there are thousnads possibilities to earn money with your new skills, or: Join other people with the same interest and just have fun  But also, it&amp;rsquo;s insanely hard after a long day of work to get enough headspace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opening the machines</title>
      <link>http://gruberbastian.com/post/openmachine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 10:37:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gruberbastian.com/post/openmachine/</guid>
      <description>I am taking a break from the working world at the moment, and just finished travelling through North America for the last 3 months. Being back at my partner&amp;rsquo;s parents&amp;rsquo; home in Canada, I browsed through the typical tech news at the end of a year. New iPhones here, better Google Pixels there. But, I am trying to apply a new rule for myself: Only buy something new if you have needed it every day for the past 30 days (with some minor exceptions of course).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git proficiency with rebase</title>
      <link>http://gruberbastian.com/post/gitprof/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 18:37:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gruberbastian.com/post/gitprof/</guid>
      <description>I am a developer now for more than 10 years. Except a few years with SVN, I was solely working with Git. The best quote I got from one of my CTOs in the early days, was:
&amp;ldquo;Git is like the whole world, but we need just the size of a lake of it.&amp;rdquo;
You mainly use:
 git clone git pull git push git add git commit git checkout and git checkout -b  That&amp;rsquo;s mostly it, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching back to Sublime Text</title>
      <link>http://gruberbastian.com/post/switch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 10:40:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gruberbastian.com/post/switch/</guid>
      <description>Since the beginning of JavaScript on the desktop, aka Electron, I was happily switching to GitHubs Atom text editor. The benefits are obvious:
 Open Source Written in JavaScript, my main langauge Comes from a cool brand Faster development cycles  Ever since I switched, I loved Atom. Many plugins are enhancing your life as a developer. A few glitches here and there didn&amp;rsquo;t let me question my decision a few years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get started with BeagleBone</title>
      <link>http://gruberbastian.com/post/go-beaglebone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 10:20:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gruberbastian.com/post/go-beaglebone/</guid>
      <description>I have to admit, the power of IoT did not yet reach my little nerd life here in Berlin. Therefore, I took an effort this year and went to an IoT Hackathon. It was a fun weekend, I think there were just 5 developers and the rest of the crowd came from a social and educational background. Which made it even more fun and interesting.
Anyway, since this weekend I ordered a RaspberryPi and tried to do something useful with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downsizing and its side effects</title>
      <link>http://gruberbastian.com/post/sideeffects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 09:51:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gruberbastian.com/post/sideeffects/</guid>
      <description>For quite a long time now, I have been reading these two books:
 Early Retirement Extreme Your Money or Your Life  These titles suggest that it&amp;rsquo;s all about earning lots of money and then coasting your way through life. After reading the first few pages however, it becomes clear that the goal of these books is to provide you with a new mindset.
You can see all the hipsters in big cities are trying to do the same: eat locally, cook your own food, be aware of the consequences of your actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The beauty of DevOps</title>
      <link>http://gruberbastian.com/post/devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 20:37:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gruberbastian.com/post/devops/</guid>
      <description>For my latest client, I got hired as a Fullstack JavaScript developer, plus DevOps, plus Frontend. The project is to rebuild the old PHP codebase onto a new stack containing Node, Angular and Microservices. The deployment is done via Docker and DockerCloud, hosted partly on AWS servers. As complicated as it sounds, new projects don&amp;rsquo;t have the nitty gritty problems legacy systems have. I think what you have to bring to such a project is a broad understanding of each technology and how they interact together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Usedum in fall</title>
      <link>http://gruberbastian.com/post/usedum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 14:37:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gruberbastian.com/post/usedum/</guid>
      <description>Hectic and grey Berlin is vibrant, always “on” and full of inspirational people. If you are looking for something, you will find it. But, what makes the city such a astounding place to live in, is also the reason why it is draining your energy and emotions. Not alone this, but the architecture of big and wide streets and sometimes narrow and huge houses are great in the summer, but aweful to look at in Winter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pet Projects</title>
      <link>http://gruberbastian.com/post/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 14:37:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gruberbastian.com/post/projects/</guid>
      <description> All the little things  iOS app: Calculator [Swift] Webservice: Bookmarking backend [Golang] Command line: Number guessing [Rust] Command line: Image AI [NodeJS, GoogleVisionAPI] Command line: Who unfollowed you on twitter? [Python] 
Grown up projects Claudia Castrone Portfolio ( | )  Good old jQuery Foundation 6 JavaScript HTML5/CSS3 Heroku  LivingRoomArt ()  Frontend: AngularJS Backend: NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB Deployment: Heroku FileUpload: Amazon S3  OpenDecision ()  Frontend: AngularJS Backend: NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB Deployment: Heroku  ChartistDirective ()  AngularJS  CompanyLunch ()  Frontend: ReactJS Backend: NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB Deployment: Heroku  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://gruberbastian.com/post/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 16:37:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gruberbastian.com/post/about/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s me, Bastian, a passionate software developer. I am using Go, JavaScript and HTML/CSS to create web applications, and always keen and happy to help a software project to thrive. Next to coding I am a tech writer, mostly for Apple magazines. I also contribute to various german tech magazines. Those two professions let me earn enough money to appreciate and learn other hobbies like photography and improvisation theatre.
It&amp;rsquo;s hard to define languages and skills, since I am constantly challenged with new architectures, ideas and platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>