<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bastian Gruber</title>
    <link>http://gruberbastian.com/tags/development/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bastian Gruber</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://gruberbastian.com/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>No more Websites</title>
      <link>http://gruberbastian.com/post/no-websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 14:40:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gruberbastian.com/post/no-websites/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-we-should-abandon-the-idea-of-a-websites&#34;&gt;Why we should abandon the idea of a websites&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the new shift in the Front End world of JS, there is a huge tendency of seeing a web application as the sum of its components. Instead of navigating (or routing) to a HTML file, Angular 2, for example, is routing to a component. ReactJS is doing the same. Building a bunch of components, bundling them and making the result available through a certain route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This direction let me think: What are websites nowadays? With the emerge of IoT, and micro controllers talking to each other, what does a website really say? Sure, corporations, small companies and bloggers have their own &amp;ldquo;website&amp;rdquo;. But is it really a website? And should we call it that way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are open source advocates out there who fight for an open and free web. Who dismiss the idea of Apps, because they are hold my larger corporations inside a store, and cannot get modified and it&amp;rsquo;s not easy to see what they are up to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why aren&amp;rsquo;t we looking at the bigger picture? In times where the internet is as important as electricity, and software who runs our bookkeeping and access to important &amp;ldquo;sites&amp;rdquo;, you have to ask yourself? Has the internet grown out of browser based websites and small blogs?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I am thinking of, is: Forget Facebook, forget LinkedIn, screw Google. The digital space is much more like the real one. Why should I create an account at LinkedIn and Facebook? In addition, why should I think of publishing my news on Facebook or connect on twitter? Those solutions all grew out of their original thoughts. They started and advanced the simple website business, and they built web applications accessable by a browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 21st century, I, as a citizen of the world, should have the right for my own domain with my name and fake name. I should have an identity online with which I trade, connect and act. A simple like is so far just a &lt;code&gt;like_count++&lt;/code&gt;. But my Like should have a voice, and a character. With the real my behind it. Why should we try to map the real world with algorithms and map it to the internet? We are the internet. We are also not the internet. The digital space merged with the physical one. Decisions are based daily upon algorithms and code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Privacy advocates will jump up and say: &amp;ldquo;But we are not protected. It should be anonymous. Governments will track you down if you try to challenge their power.&amp;rdquo; But wait a minute: There is no government. There are no &amp;ldquo;other people&amp;rdquo;. We are as the world population the people. We decide what we say and what we do. There are rules out there, but somebody has to impose them, follow them through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We shouldn&amp;rsquo;t continue try hiding and keep ourselves private. There is no privacy out there. We should rather work on destroying judgmental behaviour and talking our freedom down. We will all die in the end. Nobody leaves with wold alive. Instead of hiding, writing our blogs and building websites, we should create online and offline identities, act with them and behave like free people. We all can change the law. We decide if we act on harrsement and violation of personal rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the emerge of IoT, free WiFi everywhere, smaller and more powerful devices, we have to learn that there is no distingion between offline and online. There is no difference where we act how. The simple websites with a contact form is gone, and a new, more powerful version has arrived: An online identity which can act and challenge structures much faster, and with a wider reach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, instead of learning a new framework or a new tool, built yourself online. Think for yourself how you want to be seen and how this new world should look like.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pet Projects</title>
      <link>http://gruberbastian.com/post/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 14:37:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gruberbastian.com/post/projects/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;livingroomart-a-href-https-github-com-gruberb-livingroomart-i-class-fa-fa-github-aria-hidden-true-i-a-a-href-http-livingroomart-frontend-herokuapp-com-i-class-fa-fa-globe-aria-hidden-true-i-a&#34;&gt;LivingRoomArt (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gruberb/LivingRoomArt&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-github&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;http://livingroomart-frontend.herokuapp.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-globe&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/gruberb-blog/Bildschirmfoto+2016-11-04+um+2.17.33+PM.png&#34; title=&#34;LivingroomArt&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frontend: AngularJS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backend: NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deployment: Heroku&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FileUpload: Amazon S3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;opendecision-a-href-https-github-com-gruberb-opendecision-i-class-fa-fa-github-aria-hidden-true-i-a-a-href-https-opendecision-frontend-herokuapp-com-registration-i-class-fa-fa-globe-aria-hidden-true-i-a&#34;&gt;OpenDecision (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gruberb/OpenDecision&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-github&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;https://opendecision-frontend.herokuapp.com/#/registration&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-globe&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/gruberb-blog/Bildschirmfoto+2016-11-04+um+2.36.23+PM.png&#34; title=&#34;OpenDecision&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frontend: AngularJS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backend: NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deployment: Heroku&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;chartistdirective-a-href-https-github-com-gruberb-chartistangulardirective-i-class-fa-fa-github-aria-hidden-true-i-a&#34;&gt;ChartistDirective (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gruberb/chartistAngularDirective&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-github&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/gruberb-blog/Bildschirmfoto+2016-11-04+um+2.39.08+PM.png&#34; title=&#34;ChartistDirective&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AngularJS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;companylunch-a-href-https-github-com-gruberb-companylunch-i-class-fa-fa-github-aria-hidden-true-i-a-a-href-https-companylunch-frontend-herokuapp-com-i-class-fa-fa-globe-aria-hidden-true-i-a&#34;&gt;CompanyLunch (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gruberb/CompanyLunch&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-github&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;https://companylunch-frontend.herokuapp.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-globe&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/gruberb-blog/Bildschirmfoto+2016-11-04+um+2.40.20+PM.png&#34; title=&#34;CompanyLunch&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frontend: ReactJS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backend: NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deployment: Heroku&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>